Amiya Kumar Sahoo () Featured

Sr. Software Engineer seeking roles in Software Development, Application
Programming, Requirement Gathering, Project Management, System Analysis, Agile
Methodology, Cloud Computing, Configuration Management, Client
Management, Spring, Java, Maven



Current Designation: Sr. Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Legato Health Technology Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Sr. Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Requirement Gathering, Project Management, System Analysis, Agile Methodology, Cloud Computing, Configuration Management, Client

Management, Spring, Java, Maven, Apache

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Having 5 years of experience in Information Technology as a developer using Java/J2EE technologies.

Experience in development and implementation on Client/Server and web based applications using Java/J2EE technologies. Having good experience in Jenkins Build Pipeline, Maven & CICD Configuration.

Experience in Talend ETL Tool and Facets.

Working various batch job related to EDI like 837I, 837P, 270, 271, 276, and 277.

Having good experience in advanced frame works like Spring-JDBC, Hibernate, Spring Boot, Spring IOC, web services, Spring Cloud Gateway.

Hands of Experience in Tomcat7, JBOSS and OSE.

Having Extensive experience Restful Web Services.

Having Knowledge in SOAP and XML Schema's.

Having Knowledge and Experience in Micro services.

DB Skills with various databases like oracle, MySQL.

Having good knowledge in Spring ORM using with Hibernate.

Involved in both Waterfall and Agile Methodlogy.

Work Experience

Legato Health Technology as Sr. Software Engineer Sep 2019 to Till Date

Artech Infosystems as Software Engineer Sep 2015 to Mar 2016

software engineer

UHG as Software Engineer Apr 2015 to Aug 2019

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Utkal University in 2010

PG: MCA (Computers) from Biju Patnaik University of Technology (BPUT) in 2013

IT Skills

Skill Name WINDOWS	Version	Last Used	Experience
java, PL/SQL			
JDBC, Servlets, JSP			
Spring, Hibernate, Spring Boot.			
Web Services, XML, XSD			
Oracle11g,Oracle 12c			
Hibernate			
JUnit, Log4j, Maven,Gradle			
Eclipse			
TALEND			
Apache Tomcat,JBoss7			
SVN, Git Hub, BitBucket			
Jenkins,Bambo			

Affirmative Action

Category: General

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time